<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Us on ieahts.org</title>
    <link>https://ieahts.org/about-us/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Us on ieahts.org</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 11:45:58 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ieahts.org/about-us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Contact Information</title>
      <link>https://ieahts.org/about-us/contact-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 11:45:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ieahts.org/about-us/contact-info/</guid>
      <description>CountryNominationName and OrganizationExecutive CommitteeCanadaAlternateDr. Frédéric Sirois Polytechnique Montréal
GermanyAlternateDr. Tabea Arndt Karlsruhe Institute of Technology
DelegateProf. Mathias Noe Karlsruhe Institute of Technology
AlternateProf. Bernhard Holzapfel Karlsruhe Institute of Technology
ItalyDelegateLaura Serri (Chair) Ricerca sul Sistema Energetico – RSE S.p.A.
AlternateGiuliano Angeli Ricerca sul Sistema Energetico – RSE S.p.A.
AlternateAngela Olichini Ricerca sul Sistema Energetico – RSE S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>https://ieahts.org/about-us/the-iea-tcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 11:27:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ieahts.org/about-us/the-iea-tcp/</guid>
      <description>Members of the Executive Committee include senior persons engaged in research, development and demonstration and persons who manage those efforts. Each institution chooses its representatives according to its own needs. Members of the Executive Committee take turns serving as host to the twice yearly Executive Committee Meeting. These meetings are the venue for face-to-face discussion. In addition, the host complements these discussions by arranging presentations from national experts and/or tours of whatever facilities the host deems appropriate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Direction</title>
      <link>https://ieahts.org/about-us/strategic-direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 10:45:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ieahts.org/about-us/strategic-direction/</guid>
      <description>The HTS TCP conducts outreach toward electric utilities, governments, the professional engineering community, and the RD&amp;amp;D community to communicate the potential benefits of HTS technology.&amp;nbsp; Examples of this outreach include:
Developing position papers and strategic documents such as roadmaps and technical reportsProviding expertise that can inform the evaluations and assessments performed under the TCPInteracting with other related TCPs to leverage synergies and opportunitiesDisseminating our work at international forums and workshops and educate students, young engineers, and scientists about HTS applications in the power sectorAddress and clarify perceived risks and hurdles to introduce a disruptive technology into the conservative electric power industryThe HTS TCP has developed a number of publications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
